#### Contact

03157721671 (Home) usamafarooq2007@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/usamafarooq-b6a3b9a5 (LinkedIn) relaxed-volhard-611221.netlify.app/ (Portfolio)

### Top Skills

NestJS

Next.js

Node js

### Languages

Urdu (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)

# Usama Farooq

Full Stack Software Engineer at SmashCloud

Lahore District, Punjab, Pakistan

## Summary

Hi, there

I'm a seasoned Full Stack Developer with a deep focus on the MERN stack, bringing over 6 years of experience in crafting robust web and mobile applications. Specializing in React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, and Express, I have developed a wide array of E-Commerce platforms, Marketplace platforms, Content Management Systems, and various web applications.

✓# Frontend React.js

HTML / CSS3 / Bootstrap #

Responsive Web Design / Mobile First Design #

Material UI / Ant Design / Tailwind CSS #

React JS / React Hooks / Routing #

React-Redux / Context API #

Next JS#

Unit Testing #

TypeScript #

Git#

Google Maps / JS Charts #

√# Backend Node.js Application

Node JS / Express JS #

MongoDB / Sequelize #

Micro Services Architecture #

AWS (AWS Serverless, S3, EC2)#

✓# DevOps Experience

Extensive Experience on Amazon Web Services (CI/CD)

Deployments on Salesforce/Heroku

Preparing for AWS Certified Cloud Practioner Certification

Connect with Me:

Please have a look into my GitHub repository particularly for React JS Code in here

https://github.com/Usama125/medicapp-react

Please have a look into my GitHub repository particularly for Node JS Code in here

https://github.com/Usama125/medicapp

Let's have a look into my portfolio site as well

Portfolio Website: https://relaxed-volhard-611221.netlify.app/ Resume Website: https://clever-fermi-a94768.netlify.app/

Hope for fruitful cooperation.

Thanks

## Experience

SmashCloud Full Stack Engineer August 2022 - Present (3 years) Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

BIG IMMERSIVE
Full Stack Developer ( MERN )
October 2021 - September 2022 (1 year)
Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

NETSOL Technologies Inc. Software Engineer November 2020 - October 2021 (1 year)

Nextbridge Ltd.
Full Stack JavaScript Engineer
September 2019 - November 2020 (1 year 3 months)
Johar town Lahore

LEADConcept
React.js Developer
October 2018 - September 2019 (1 year)

Lahore, Pakistan

## Education

University Of Surgodha

BS Software Engineering, Information Technology · (2014 - 2018)

Page 3 of 3